=Remnants of Gold=
(Adapted from Gu Long's
"Flying Eagle over the Great Land")
(The main characters
in this drama are fictional)
=Episode 9=
I don't believe you
won't sleep all night.
I couldn't sleep anyway.
Why couldn't you sleep?
There are many things
I need to ask Deputy Yu.
I don't believe you
would stab me with a spear.
I don't believe it, either.
But whatever Deputy Yu orders, you do?
I am Deputy Yu's soldier.
You're amazing.
The General is my superior,
and Deputy Yu is my brother.
If the General and Deputy Yu
order me to die,
I die.
Still, I don't believe you
would stab me with a spear.
Burning so much dry grass?
This is enchanting grass
my guy brought over
from the Western Regions.
Burn it all up.
What are they doing?
They are people who bury Tie Futu.
Luckily, there was a merchant caravan,
so I asked them for help.
You can get people to help bury bodies?
For two camels and two bags of salt,
people would even help bury the living.
You don't want the salt and camels?
At daybreak,
I must hurry to kill my guy.
Taking camels is too slow.
Who are you?
You arrived late during the day.
Wasn't everyone looking
for the guardians of the gold?
They found?
I am one.
Bana from the camel-horse market
at Lieyang Well is one, too.
He and his son were captured by
Deputy Military Commissioner Yu.
I have to rush over to kill him.
However, I don't know
if I can actually bring myself to do it.
I couldn't bring myself
to do it during the day.
Are there really 300,000 taels of gold?
Those 300,000 taels of gold
were buried by Koke Temur,
Right Chancellor of Yuan.
Koke-what?
The Right Chancellor's
Han name was Wang Baobao.
In the 28th year of Zhizheng,
which was the first year of Hongwu,
Emperor Taizu captured Dadu.
The Right Chancellor
suffered a crushing defeat at Taiyuan,
escaping to Gansu with only 18 riders.
Bana, myself,
and 16 other guys
were those 18 riders.
Only a year later,
in the second year of Hongwu,
the Right Chancellor gathered 100,000
elite troops to besiege Lanzhou,
ordering us to bury
those 300,000 taels of gold
for future grand plans.
We became guardians of the gold
that very year.
But why didn't the Right Chancellor
come back to retrieve the gold?
In the third year of Hongwu,
Wang Baobao suffered
a massive defeat and fled to Karakorum.
In the eighth year of Hongwu,
he passed away.
Your guy was captured,
yet you're rushing over to kill him?
He wants to take Liangzhou Deputy
to the Right Chancellor's gold.
Deputy Military Commissioner
Yu Hou of Liangzhou.
Do you want to know where the gold is
now, too?
No.
Then, I won't have to kill you.
Are we still friends?
Go to Wusu Sea.
My yurt will be your yurt.
My friend,
I'm not interested
in that gold right now.
But it's not because I'm afraid of you.
I know.
He's gone!
He left!
- Who's gone?
- Who left?
He's gone.
It's the kid.
His kid.
Keep an eye on him.
Hurry, follow Deputy Yu and pursue.
Fang.
Quick.
Follow Deputy Yu, quick.
What are you staring at? Don't move.
Fang!
- Fang!
Fang.
Search everywhere.
- Yes, sir!
Fang!
Run again, and I'll kill you.
I don't believe you will.
Fang.
Help me.
Chase. Quick, chase him!
All right.
Father...
Shut up.
There's no outsider here.
Hurry, go.
Son,
go.
Go where?
As far away as possible.
What about you?
Hurry, go.
Deputy Military Commissioner!
Hou,
you didn't say it'd turn out like this
on Liangzhou's city wall.
I'm asking you, Deputy.
Where's the kid?
I don't know.
You dare disobey orders?
I'll go kill him myself.
I'll go.
I'll go kill him now.
Father.
He's dead!
You might as well die, too!
Tie them both up.
- Yes, sir!
What is this?
Yellow pea cake.
Made from the best peas in Eastern Shu.
Pingping was carrying it on her back.
After everything's over,
go back to Northern Shu's Tang Clan?
If I go back to the Tang Clan,
I'll be like a scorpion,
a centipede, or a lizard.
Before, Pingping treated me as a human.
Five years ago, when I got married,
I fell off a cliff
while crossing the Shu Road.
It took me three days to climb back up.
By the time I reached the Tang Clan,
I had become a cripple.
So they used me as a poison tester.
They tested all kinds of poison on me.
I went through living heck.
Why?
Didn't you marry into the Tang Clan?
It was my betrothed
who tested poisons on me.
He was born a cripple
and wanted to be like you.
After three years of testing poisons,
going through living heck many times,
I was no longer crippled,
but he still couldn't move.
The yin energy in his body
grew heavier and heavier.
It was like...
Like a transparent person.
I saw him.
Impossible.
At Heisong Post,
when I went to the second floor
to talk to you,
a transparent person
was right outside your door.
He vanished in the blink of an eye.
Maybe my eyes were playing tricks on me.
Then, Tie Futu showed up.
You saw wrong.
He's still a cripple,
unable to move.
Is the yellow pea cake good?
Everything comes to an end eventually.
If you won't return to the Tang Clan,
where will you go?
What counts as an end?
Tie Futu won't get away.
All land under heaven
belongs to the King.
You will catch him and kill him?
Too many people have died already.
Bring him to justice...
Whose justice?
Gansu is a major
stronghold in the Northwest,
with twelve guards and four battalions.
With one order,
thousands of troops
and assassin mercenaries respond.
What if
it was the Commander-in-Chief
who murdered and robbed
for those 300,000 taels of gold?
Impossible.
You can't go to Ganzhou
just for this minor affair
of my family.
You can't see the General
and ask why he murdered and robbed.
You can't say to the General
that all land
under heaven belongs to the King.
Can't I?
I'll go ask Bancha if he
wants some yellow pea cake.
Delicious.
You never knew
that your guy had a son?
My men only know
that Bana has a boy named Seventeen.
Actually, you knew
that Seventeen is his son.
Really delicious.
You can't kill Bana.
It's a piece of cake.
I mean,
you
can't kill Bana.
Kill whoever tries to find the gold.
Kill as many as there are.
Even if thousands of troops come,
charge at them.
That's what the Right Chancellor
said at the time.
Right Chancellor?
Wang Baobao.
So that's how it is.
You are a warrior
of the Yuan's Right Chancellor,
Koke Temur.
You're quite smart.
You know everything.
Since you are in a hurry to kill,
why don't you travel through the night?
The dead souls here
need someone to see them off.
I will set off when the fire goes out.
I will make it in time.
I've met three types of people.
The first type is good people.
The second type is evil people.
The third type
is good people turning into evil ones.
But I don't know which type you are.
I will only know when I die.
Good people go to heaven,
and evil people go to the underworld.
Have you been at the Wusu Sea
for the past 30 years?
There is no better place in the world
than the Wusu Sea.
How good is it?
It's just like heaven.
I really want to go.
You can go, too.
Good people go to heaven.
Can I ask a favor of you?
Sure.
If a fight breaks out at Shiquan Fort,
let Fang live.
Okay.
Tell him that Pingping went to heaven.
Tell him
to stop believing in their General.
Where do you want to go?
Let's part ways here.
This time,
it was nice to meet you.
I also want to know
where you want to go.
I want to know
if you really never lie.
No.
How can a person not lie?
Fang,
who am I?
Fang.
Deputy.
Who am I?
Hou!
I tied you up.
I will let you go after we talk.
What is there left to say?
What to say?
You have killed people.
At 15, you went to guard the frontier.
In five years, you fought seven battles.
Seventeen people died under your spear.
That was killing the enemy.
It is not the same!
Don't shout.
Speak calmly.
I can hear you.
Miss Zhang's
27 family members...
Was it you
and Tie Futu who poisoned them?
Yes.
But you were on the city wall,
clearly asking me to protect her
and do
whatever she says.
I want the gold.
300,000 taels.
What do you need the gold for?
I don't want to spend
my whole life in the great desert.
I don't want to go out every day
to the scorching sun and yellow sand.
In Jiangnan,
there are fireworks and willows.
Everything is expensive.
Hou,
are you going to leave?
I don't want to spend my whole life
growing old and dying in this place.
So you killed Miss Zhang's whole family.
So you killed the guardian of the gold!
You killed Bana.
Hou!
Doing this, does your conscience
really not bother you?
It doesn't.
You only live once.
A real man
must cut ties decisively.
I don't believe it.
You're not that kind of person.
I am that kind of person.
I am that kind of person!
I've told you now.
What will the General
think of you doing this?
Is this how you repay the General?
If you leave,
what will the General think?
You once said
the General
is like an older brother to you,
just like you are to me, Deputy!
Once you've stood on these city walls
for another 20 years,
you'll become just like me.
No amount of torture could make me.
I like those city walls.
I like the great desert.
I like the hot sun.
I like it all.
I won't let you down, Deputy.
Once the rope is untied,
you won't fight me, will you?
Not even if I die!
You can leave now.
Don't look back.
Or you can
lie down and get some sleep.
Tomorrow morning,
head toward Shiquan Fort.
The guardians of the gold
will give chase.
You've made enemies of them.
Keep an eye on that kid.
Enemies over what?
You killed a guardian of the gold,
who is that kid's father.
How bold of you.
How dare you accuse
the Commander-in-Chief of Gansu
of murder and robbery.
So you want to punish me
for that, Officer Pu?
You can't just throw
wild accusations around.
Just take it as me
spouting nonsense then.
It's not like you can
go question the General.
Even if you asked,
what if he denies it?
Even if he admits it,
what can the imperial court do?
It's only natural for him
to want former dynasty gold.
My father and brothers
were just commoners.
How do you know it was the General?
I just know.
How do you know?
Though I've never met the General,
I know what kind of man
Deputy Yu of Liangzhou is.
Collusion between officials and bandits
was the General's order.
Did Deputy Yu tell you that?
Bancha said
not all hatred can be avenged.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
Where will you go?
Not back to Northern Shu, for sure.
Maybe I'll go
to Jiangnan.
What do you mean?
This matter isn't over yet.
Go back to the Capital.
If you feel this isn't over,
go back and report
to the imperial court.
That would be helping me.
The court might send
another imperial envoy
who can actually get
the General to tell the truth.
If the imperial will is unpredictable
and nothing comes of it,
Officer Pu,
you must live and act as you did before.
Forget everything
that happened in Gansu.
Forget me, too.
It's very easy to forget.
That's all?
We'll go our separate ways at dawn,
never to meet again in this life.
That's all?
You're a good person.
Good people should live a long life.
I never expected it
to turn out like this.
I'm going to sleep.
Safe travels at dawn, Officer Pu.
The girl is buried right here?
It's the best we can do.
It'll be the same for you when you die?
When I die,
I want to be buried in Wusu Sea.
Bancha said
there is no better place
in this world than Wusu Sea.
How good is it?
Like heaven.
You won't die.
I'm leaving.
Without you,
I have no family left in this world.
Nothing to tie me down,
and nothing to fear.
(Ganzhou)
Move!
Move.
This way.
Come take a look.
(Shaquan Inn)
Just one person?
I'm looking for someone.
Who are you looking for?
The person I'm looking for
is staying in your best room.
I'm looking for
Qin Demon of Mount Pingfeng.
Hold on a second.
I still think
the water at Mount Pingfeng is better.
Earlier you said,
between Ganzhou and Xining,
this inn in Ganzhou had the best water.
Now, you're back to
praising Mount Pingfeng's water.
Qin Demon wanted to bathe?
He made me
come all the way to Ganzhou to see him.
You're unhappy every time you come out.
And everything costs so much.
Which of you
is the Qin Demon of Mount Pingfeng?
(Preview of the Next Episode)
What sorcery
does this guqin have?
Who killed Bana?
I did.
Let me show you what I've got.
Form up.
Divine machinery.
Tie Futu,
the superior officer
ordered your arrest.
Surrender at once.
=Remnants of Gold=